We've seen that the HTTP POST protocol is very convenient to connect our LoRaWAN server to the IoT
platform.
It works for the uplink stream and also to send downlink messages.
Now let's stop for a few second and try to analyze the HTTP POST behavior.
First, let's imagine that we want to connect another IoT platform.
In that case, we need to go on the LoRaWAN server and to configure a new server that needs to be
connected.
It was not very complicated because we just had to provide the URL endpoint, but still we have to do
it.
Secondly, when we created this integration on the LoRaWAN server we defined which event had to be sent.
In our case, we decided to send all uplink data.
If your application needs more information, let's say the join accept frames, or acknowledgment,
then we need to go back on the server to configure it.
Again, it's not complicated, but still you have to do it.
The third point is that if for some reason your IoT platform is disconnected for a few seconds, then
the HTTP request will not reach your endpoint.
There is a good chance that your data will be definitely lost.
And finally, in some situation, the HTTP client can think that the request has not been received,
whereas the endpoint had received the message.
That could lead to duplicate messages on the IoT platform.
However, the HTTP POST method is widely used, so we absolutely not consider it's a bad way to connect
the LoRaWAN server with the IoT platform.
But we'll see now,
another way to connect them.
It's actually a new protocol that we are going to explain.
It supports duplicate messages, the disconnection.
I will also be a lightweight protocol in order to deal with thousands of potential connection at the
same time.
This protocol is called MQTT.
It's going to be the topic of the next video.